[Music]
focus
innovate enable
icici lombard and cnbc tv 18 present
india risk management awards risk master
class
a very good evening ladies and gentlemen
i'm radu bhandari
welcome to the risk master class 2020
under the ages of the
india risk management awards brought to
you by itici lombard
general insurance company and cnbc tva
team
this year successive lockdowns around
the world have also forced
businesses to rethink their risk
management strategies
remodel their businesses in many cases
and stay
up to speed as far as compliance and
safety issues are concerned
geopolitical risks have also been on the
rise as a result of the pandemic
and therefore global supply chains have
often seen disruption
as india embraces the fourth industrial
revolution
where the old complex and formerly
closed environments
solutions as well as systems will meet
new connected and open ones
risk frameworks are also set for a
tremendous change
so what's really important in this
scenario well to be alert for one
and implement the right kind of controls
take swift action to mitigate risk
and really stay at the front
of this multifaceted crisis this risk
master class will help you do
just that today our focus is on many
critical sectors of the economy
including
it ites metals and mining telecom
insurance healthcare and more so let's
kick off the evening by learning a
little bit about some of the new age
risks
affordable risk management strategies
and of course technology solutions that
can be used
for risk mitigation in a boundary-less
organizations
and for this executive address i'd like
to welcome sahil kangostrom vice
president corporate solutions group
icici lombard general insurance company
over to you sal
thanks window good evening everyone on
behalf of ics lombard
and cnbc tea team i send a warm welcome
to you
thanks all for connecting with us today
we believe in partnering
with our clients to ensure that they are
equipped with the best risk management
and mitigation solution
to effectively handle these drifts few
of them will be insurable
whereas some may not be insurable but
we can work along with our clients to
fight innovative
and cost effective ways of reducing risk
over the years we have positioned
ourselves as this solution provider
and not just an insurer who provides you
with coverage capacity and settles the
claims path
with this introvert we have introduced
marine transit risk
of prevention activity iot for fire
hydrants
wellness solution in health space
virtual risk assessment
using drones and many more
this approach has led to reduction of
claims
and has been really appreciated by our
customers
one of the unique offering that i would
like to highlight is transit risk for
temperature sensitive cargo
where we can monitor movement of the
cargo 24 7 across the globe
and prevent or minimize losses using gps
technology
we believe it will play a very vital
role during
provide 19 vaccine transit
this brings me to the last part of my
speech
while most of us have put immediate
measures in place to ensure business
continuity
let's understand this in detail from our
eminent speakers
and powerpack panel today as how they
manage this for their organizations
i am sure each one of us will learn a
lot from their insights
thank you very much sahil well up next
we have our keynote speaker for this
risk class she's someone who's at the
helm of affairs of
india's first private health care
provider she has been
at the forefront of facing and managing
risks
while aiding the war on kovic 19 along
with her tireless teams
of health care workers so let's hear it
from dr sangeeta reddy joint mv of the
apollo hospital
group and president of vicky dr reddy
hello now how has kovid19 improve
access to healthcare across the country
this is a very interesting question
because the pandemic opened up a
plethora of opportunities which will
lead to a transform healthcare delivery
system
including newer care delivery models
enhance use of digital tools and other
technologies
a greater focus on preventive and
primary care
along with points of care and home based
testing
restructured facilities and operating
models and to boost
the local manufacturing as well as rnd
for products and treatment all focused
on better health outcomes in the country
so all these are changes which came upon
us during the kovit period but i think
will definitely stay with us
to tackle the highly infectious disease
that we have been
able to create additional health
infrastructure
enhanced human resources and indigenous
production
of critical medical equipment and
consumables
such as ppe n95 mask ventilators
and the diagnostic capability and all
this in a period of a few months
who had also opened up the opportunity
for indigenisation of medical devices
including testing equipment indigenous
kit manufacturing
and today the country has 90 forward 19
test kit manufacturers and have also
been able to augment the production of
highly specialized
equipment like ventilators hovid has
also produced
and provided opportunities to explore
new business models and avenues uh
focused on digitalization
home health care witnessed a paradigm
shift with
people using helplines teleconsults home
sample collections remote monitoring of
asymptomatic as well as positive
patients who are mildly symptomatic
and an increased focus on primary and
preventive healthcare
has really been one of the most
important aspects
as well as a host of authorized or
unauthorized
so-called immunity boosters thank you dr
sangeeta already appreciate
you joining us here today and of course
it's truly commendable how healthcare
workers around the world
have carried on against the pandemic all
of this year
up next we're shifting the focus on to
technology
digital transformation has seen
tremendous acceleration
in 2020 and has been the backbone of
keeping businesses
as well as personal connections alive in
these times of
social distancing so let's hear more in
a special address from
anush naziman he's the chief financial
officer
of cisco india and sag welcome vijay
it's a pleasure to be able to address
the distinguished group
or form of individuals business leaders
we are going to talk about a topic that
is so intrinsic and close to us
if i may say in the last few months
as winston churchill says we should
never let go of
a crisis to waste this is the chance for
all cfos to look at operational
investments
where we could improve where we are
actually spending a lot of redundant
cost
this is the window of opportunity cisco
for example
when we looked at all our customers who
are actually undergoing
changes to their own models which are
moving to hybrid they were working on a
lot of automation
we also moved a lot of our products into
a service model
what happens with that is there is more
predictability of revenue
for us at the same time the capacity
pressure on the clients is much much
lower
finally the cfo needs to be worried
about how to manage risks
be it with suppliers partners and
customers
scenario building continuously working
closely with them
the the environment of fraud today there
are a lot of layoffs the employees are
very disengaged
these things can actually lead to frauds
within the company
the cfo needs to invest more on internal
controls we can't let them down in terms
of how we're trying to do this
finally the cyber attacks we need to be
clear
there is a clear investment going into
security
we adopt all the latest technologies to
safeguard assets and our data from
these sort of threats end of the day
it's important
that we continue to be focused on
operational improvements
and cash focus to continue through this
crisis
given the uncertainty and depth of the
duration of this covet
cfos have to continuously engage in
scenario planning to identify
where risks are likely to their impact
their company
thank you very much for sharing your
insights and experiences with i
appreciate you joining us here today
next up i would like to invite prague
who's the executive director of pwc
india to share his findings
on how the risk management landscape is
evolving and also give us an overview of
creating a best-in-class
risk management program welcome frank
uh thanks middle um it's a pleasure to
be connected
with all of you uh look forward to
sharing some insights on the risk
management practices that we are seeing
across
what really is risk management and you
know
why companies have to adopt it um i will
not use any jargons to define
what is risk management what companies
should be doing
about it to put very very simply
it's a way through which
organizations determine uh the chances
of not meeting their business objectives
and i'll again give you a very simple
example uh
at a given point in time an organization
may have an objective
that they want to grow in the emerging
markets
now through an enterprise risk
management function
they'll be able to determine what could
go wrong
in the marketplace which can impact
their growth in those emerging markets
again
it is risk management is not a
compliance it is not an audit function
it is a function that prepares you for
future
and and it has number of benefits
attached to it very simply one of the
risk is that it gives you peace of mind
it gives you reasonable assurance if
the management if
if management will be able to meet the
business objectives that's been
identified
it reduces the surprise element for the
organization as well
and and largely it gives comfort to the
board that things are
working largely in place
well that was very very insightful thank
you very much prague for joining us here
today
i trt lombard and cnbc tv 18 present
india risk management awards risk master
class
icrci lombard and cnbc tv 18 present
india risk management awards risk master
class
well ladies and gentlemen we now have a
power packed panel discussion of
industry leaders and they're joining us
here for a discussion
on boundary less risk management for
critical sectors of the indian economy
let's welcome our set of panelists today
alok agarwal
executive director of ici lombard
general insurance company
amy kumar group chief information
security officer at ck builder group
banker common gs cfo of subex
banlak mundra cfo of hexagon capability
center india
and amit harlalkar deputy cfo at atlanta
nipponsfield india
welcome everyone well kobet 19 has
indeed shown us that the future
is going to be far more boundary less
and we are getting there far earlier
than we anticipated
so alok let me begin by asking you first
uh traditional risks were of course all
about
manpower safety about plant and
machinery health hazards or you know
safety on the workflow but in this new
normal that we are coping with right now
and in the new world order at large
what are some of the biggest and most
emerging uh risks and trends in risk
management that you are seeing
what are your conversations with t-suite
leaders looking like across sectors and
across scale
so what happened is that before kovaid
in the last two three years we saw the
risk that were being perceived by
various corporates to be different than
what it was earlier
so for example climate risk and cyber
security risk
these were the two risks which had come
up the chain and they were one of the
most
uh risks which were perceived
by the corporates but post covet 19 it
was quite interesting that two risks
which were relatively lower in the
pegging order
suddenly came up in the pegging order
one of them was talent risk
and the other was supply chain risk the
cyber security risk continued to remain
as a high
high on priority why talent risk
is one that people will have to retrain
people to work in this new environment
environment work from home and uh why
supply chain risk people
earlier used to diversify their supply
chain so i had so as to bring down the
risk
but this very diversification used to
increase the risk because any country
which was covered affected was uh
basically
becoming a risk as far as supply chain
is concerned so if one of the countries
from where you are getting a crucial
part or equipment or something
is kobit affected your entire entire
production goes
haywire so the these were the new trends
that were
uh visible during the kovit times venkat
if i can come to you the pandemic has
accelerated the adoption of digital
technologies
by at least a few years in fact you know
while all of this
is great for growth for agility new
fraud and security risks are also
emerging a lot of these risks are to be
dealt with the organizations
are at a crossroads on how to handle
some of these
how can organizations prepare for these
in the long run telcos and communication
service providers in particular
and other businesses as well the cxos of
of all of these businesses will have to
build a digital trust because
i think what's happening with many of
our uh decent initiatives that i've as
you have seen even with the kubernetes
trust element is extremely important and
with 5g
even more so because uh the way the the
technology is working unlike the earlier
models where
the the data used to go to the cloud
here now because of the edge computing
the the the cloud is coming closer to
the data so therefore the
risk elements are far far bigger and the
kind of solutions required
are also different uh and um
right now a lot of focus on the network
of the fighter security has been taken
care of but the application level
securities have not been fully addressed
and that's where if you look at the
biggest use case for 5d is iot security
and
since via value in that space and i can
tell you for sure in iot security
the number of zero-day attacks is
something like 150 a month
so i think the kind of solutions
companies will have to adopt
to ensure that you're not in some of
those and therefore if you security
solutions to be in place
which is users latest technologies in
terms of behavioral
ai ml it's extremely important i think
so therefore
communication services providers will
have to look at all of these
examples of how do they want to address
it and more so with finding what also
happens with a number of partners who
need to come on board
for these solutions to be rolled out to
the enterprises so therefore
how do you switch a solution a security
solution then you address risks
where these number of partners are
coming together and also
uh monitor and manage them seamlessly is
what is going to be a critical element
for
uh communications providers to look at
right indeed like you rightly said
collaboration is going to be critical
uh you know for the ecosystem to really
thrive in the 5g era
unique if i may come to you you know
like alok mentioned earlier
supply chain risk is something that is
top of the mind for everybody around the
world at this point in time
a pandemic of this nature that led to
successive lockdowns around the world
but
particularly hard on manufacturing
companies what kind of risk management
did it take to ensure
supply chain and production continuity
uh throughout this year especially at
different geographies
okay so thank you actually now you're
right
probably 19 has shown us something which
is never thought of
and the fellow panelists have really a
very valid point
so i i i was reading actually about the
words depression day of 1930s
those who have not heard for the
reference during that time
the economy got slashed and the
businesses were suffering from major
challenges
business got failed during 1930s
that time the challenge was only
business and economy
now in poverty 19 it is a matter of life
and death
and there is no reverse here secondly we
are in digital world
with covet 19 there is a different
different risk
which was not there that is also linked
to a digital risk that is one of the
challenges
right okay so let me shift focus now to
the metals and mining sector
uh of course times have been
particularly tough there as well amit
there have been operational disruptions
commodity prices have been volatile
give us a sense of your risk management
strategies in these times and can
pricing related risks be managed better
in the future
thank you thank you for having me on
this panel
uh arsenal mr nippon still acquired
src in december 2019
and we were ramping up our protection
and
in march 2020 the orbit stopped
and we were running our car at 100
kilometers per hour
and suddenly we have to slow it down to
10 kilometers per hour
it was a very serious situation for all
operating units
and especially in a situation where
demand is zero
we had never encountered a situation
where everything is shut down
and the demand comes to a standstill
during this time
we took a lot of initiative to manage
the situation
i would buffet the mitigation strategy
into four parts
first and foremost what we did was we
formed a crisis management team
and a war room which was manned 24 7.
the second major thing that we did
during this time was to ensure the
health and safety of our employees uh
the community in which we operate
and prepare sops standard operating
procedures for public guidelines
this was very critical because as you
can understand in our
industrial setup we have more than 18 to
twenty thousand people
most of them are due for that employees
and it became very critical for us to
ensure the height and safety of our
employees
the third area where we started to focus
a lot was on the business and financial
scenario analysis
i remember in the month of april when i
started to prepare these financial
scenario analysis
for our business for the next six months
we had numerous scenarios which we
prepared on shipment
with the cash flow productivity
etc and we were able to use this
scenario analysis
to make judicious decisions at that
point in time
to ensure that shipments uh and ebitda
was in line with the most profitable
scenarios for us as a business
and last but not the least what we did
was
communication communication and more
communication
uh as you mentioned uh one of the
critical things which happened during
this time was the price raised
the commodity prices the foreign
currency exchange
were all moving uh in a very volatile
way uh the critical thing for us was to
ensure that
we have appropriate hedges in place for
currency
for currency for natural gas for
commodities
to ensure that the business risks are
mitigated
right okay very interesting insights
there from all of you on your respective
risk management strategies
in these difficult times let me also
come to bangla
going forward how can global capability
centers really deal with financial risks
and ensure stability
and liquidity in weak economic cycles
and uh you know
how do you see advanced analytics
helping in this
respect particularly for upgrading
internal audit systems
what we initially did to mitigate some
of that was
we prepared a regular cash flow
statement
uh anticipating our forecasting uh what
our cash requirements would be
with a lot of simulation built into that
so that
if a scenario one comes how do we react
to it if a scenario two comes how do we
react to it so that
we are prepared for any sort of
contingency which may come our way
so in my opinion uh from uh companies
can be classified into three categories
basically
evolvers followers and observers are
those companies which probably
rely significantly on technology to
support their introverted function uh
followers would be who are slow adopters
and observers are who are either get to
start or are on the sidelines to
really understand and really assess the
real benefit of these introverted
function
uh analytics in the improved function
and thereby initiate the next set of
steps
so according to a study around 50 to 20
percent
of the organizations would fall in the
evolver category who whose primary
objective of the grc program that is
governance risk and compliance program
is to continuously evaluate the risk and
also monitor the complex environment in
which the business is operating
thank you very much gentlemen for
joining us here today and sharing those
very very valuable
insights into boundary less risk
management in the new normal
thanks very much for joining us here
today goodbye
i crt lombard and cnbc tv 18 present
in their risk management awards risk
master class
[Music]
focus innovate
enable